# Terence Hughes

New York, NY | 720-787-2632 | terencehughes450@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Medium | Portfolio

### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in Python with Flask and JavaScript with React based programming. With a background as both a chef and in restaurant management. I fell in love with code after realizing the power it has as a tool to bring ideas from a conceptual stage, into reality through practical, and creative solutions for solving real world problems. I believe communication, collaboration and work ethic are important skills when it comes to achieving success and I pride myself on possessing those skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python with Flask, SQL, SQLAlchemy, JavaScript, React, Vanilla CSS, Bootstrap, JSON, Node.js, VCL(Github), HTML

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Pocket Chef - Github | Demo

Data compilation for food truck owners to keep track of their profits and expenses with chart visualizations.

- Utilized React client-side application for a seamless front-end experience
- Developed Flask Restful-API back-end to handle data persistence and respond to fetch requests
- Implemented Bootstrap as a framework for CSS to establish a uniform look throughout the application
- Integrated Chart.js to create a practical physical display of data for the user experience

#### Toon Rater - Github | Demo

A website for sharing and voting on cartoons to see which cartoon is the most popular.

- Developed the static HTML file establishing a platform to manipulate with JavaScript
- Created a db.JSON file that served as an API end-point for all fetch requests
- Styled the webpage using Vanilla CSS creating a pleasing aesthetic for the user
- Incorporated a JavaScript file, allowing for a more dynamic website and creating functionality for the web page

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Puttery, Manhattan, NY

01/2024 - Present

### Kitchen Manager

- Oversee day-to-day kitchen operations in multiple departments, including the line, prep kitchen, and dishwashing areas
- Delegate tasks among staff to ensure productivity and proper sanitation when handling food products, while also maintaining a clean environment and equipment.
- Communicate effectively to avoid confusion and ensure everyone is on the same page throughout the working day.
- Collaborate with front-of-house staff and managers to create the best possible experience for guests.

## Bar-Taco, Denver, CO

12/2021 - 1/2023

Sous Chef

- Created new menu items, incorporating diverse cultural flavor profiles for the menu to increase customer satisfaction.
- Managed a team of 10 cooks that included creating schedules and delegating responsibilities, resulting in improved kitchen efficiency and productivity.
- Demonstrated proper practices and methods when creating and serving meals to guests, teaching others how to achieve the same level of quality.

### Aurora Glazing, Denver, CO

01/2019 - 10/2021

Traveling Glazier

- Oversaw the installation and customization of high-end retail storefronts across the United States, showcasing a proven track record of precision and craftsmanship.
- Executed comprehensive on-site assessments.
- Implemented strategic solutions to optimize glass installations.

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School, Denver, CO

8/2023 - 11/2023